Pedro Azevedo Minutentag

São Paulo, SP pedro.azvm@gmail.com +55 (11) 9 7659-3112

Summary

I am a hands-on software architect / developer who enjoys both designing and developing complex applications. Worked with both small and big teams, always focusing on bringing value with the best development practices in mind.

Have knowledge on the whole software development cycle, including planning, implementation and testing. Worked on multiple types of projects: on-premise, cloud and migration projects. As an architect I have different responsibilities, but always value being close to the development team and always being able to understand the system.

Have experience on a range of technologies, developing C# / C++ / Java / Python / Angular applications, designing and creating distributed systems and I am able to work with multiple cloud providers like AWS and Azure.

Links

Github: https://github.com/pedroaz

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/pedro-azevedo-627ab8b2/

Experience

Software Architect

RDI - Capgemini (McDonalds account)

04/2019 - Present

Started at RDI as a software developer working on the Market Adoption team. Worked for a year solving market related issues, always focusing on learning about the system and delivering as quickly as possible. Supported system which were built using C++ / C# / Java and Javascript.

Was transferred to the architecture team of the company to design and work on a new cloud application which automated deployments. Assumed more responsibilities on the design part and interacting with the client. Developed a microservices system system on azure using C# and Angular.

Later I was moved to a Transformation project where I was assigned a lead role. I currently work with over 20 squads designing functional and non-functional components. The products are C# microservices and Angular micro frontend which deployed into Windows, Linux and also target AWS and Azure. My responsibilities vary from designing API's and non-functional components, talking with the clients architects and product owners and helping the squads with architectural decisions. As well being able to do hands-on work if required and help prioritize the project.

Jr. Software Developer

Jive Investments 01/2019 - 04/2019

Worked in an asset management firm, creating data mining process with Python and managing a SQL Server database. Introduced software development processes and helped design a cloud based architecture on AWS.

Game Developer

Bridge Games 07/2018 - 12/2018

Worked in a small startup developing games using Unity3D.

Worked close to the users and wrote several C# tools to help the project developement.

Self Employed

08/2017 - 12/2017

Started a small company developing VR applications for architectural projects.

Developed Unity3D applications / AWS integrations.

Internship Program

B3

01/2016 - 07/2017

Worked in the department of credit analysis alongside statisticians and economists developing software for data analysis. Developed systems using R and Python and created web widgets using Shiny.

Skills

C#, Angular, Python, Cloud Computing, Architecture Design, Software development, Java, C++, Web Development

Education

Information System

USP

12/2018

Physics

USP

(Interrupted after 3 years)

Languages

Portuguese, English, Spanish